Now, this building had to receive two and a half thousand really highly strung thoroughbred horses that were coming off long-haul flights, highly jet-lagged, not feeling their finest. And the problem the engineer confronted was, what quantity of waste to cater for? Now, you don't get taught this in engineering school -- (Laughter) -- and it's not really the kind of thing you want to get wrong, so he could have spent months talking to vets, doing the research, tweaking the spreadsheet. Instead, he asked for help and he found someone who had designed the Jockey Club in New York. The problem was solved in less than a day. Arup believes that the culture of helpfulness is central to their success. Now, helpfulness sounds really anemic, but it's absolutely core to successful teams, and it routinely outperforms individual intelligence. Helpfulness means I don't have to know everything, I just have to work among people who are good at getting and giving help. At SAP, they reckon that you can answer any question in 17 minutes. But there isn't a single high-tech company I've worked with that imagines for a moment that this is a technology issue, because what drives helpfulness is people getting to know each other. Now that sounds so obvious, and we think it'll just happen normally, but it doesn't. When I was running my first software company, I realized that we were getting stuck. There was a lot of friction, but not much else, and I gradually realized the brilliant, creative people that I'd hired didn't know each other. They were so focused on their own individual work, they didn't even know who they were sitting next to, and it was only when I insisted that we stop working and invest time in getting to know each other that we achieved real momentum. Now, that was 20 years ago, and now I visit companies that have banned coffee cups at desks because they want people to hang out around the coffee machines and talk to each other. The Swedes even have a special term for this. They call it fika, which means more than a coffee break. It means collective restoration. At Idexx, a company up in Maine, they've created vegetable gardens on campus so that people from different parts of the business can work together and get to know the whole business that way. Have they all gone mad? Quite the opposite -- they've figured out that when the going gets tough, and it always will get tough if you're doing breakthrough work that really matters, what people need is social support, and they need to know who to ask for help. Companies don't have ideas; only people do. And what motivates people are the bonds and loyalty and trust they develop between each other. What matters is the mortar, not just the bricks. Now, when you put all of this together, what you get is something called social capital. Social capital is the reliance and interdependency that builds trust. The term comes from sociologists who were studying communities that proved particularly resilient in times of stress. Social capital is what gives companies momentum, and social capital is what makes companies robust. What does this mean in practical terms? It means that time is everything, because social capital compounds with time. So teams that work together longer get better, because it takes time to develop the trust you need for real candor and openness. And time is what builds value. When Alex Pentland suggested to one company that they synchronize coffee breaks so that people would have time to talk to each other, profits went up 15 million dollars, and employee satisfaction went up 10 percent. Not a bad return on social capital, which compounds even as you spend it. Now, this isn't about chumminess, and it's no charter for slackers, because people who work this way tend to be kind of scratchy, impatient, absolutely determined to think for themselves because that's what their contribution is. Conflict is frequent because candor is safe. And that's how good ideas turn into great ideas, because no idea is born fully formed. It emerges a little bit as a child is born, kind of messy and confused, but full of possibilities. And it's only through the generous contribution, faith and challenge that they achieve their potential. And that's what social capital supports. Now, we aren't really used to talking about this, about talent, about creativity, in this way. We're used to talking about stars. So I started to wonder, well, if we start working this way, does that mean no more stars? So I went and I sat in on the auditions at the Royal Academy of Dramatic Art in London. And what I saw there really surprised me, because the teachers weren't looking for individual pyrotechnics. They were looking for what happened between the students, because that's where the drama is. And when I talked to producers of hit albums, they said, "Oh sure, we have lots of superstars in music. It's just, they don't last very long. It's the outstanding collaborators who enjoy the long careers, because bringing out the best in others is how they found the best in themselves." And when I went to visit companies that are renowned for their ingenuity and creativity, I couldn't even see any superstars, because everybody there really mattered. And when I reflected on my own career, and the extraordinary people I've had the privilege to work with, I realized how much more we could give each other if we just stopped trying to be superchickens. (Laughter) (Applause) Once you appreciate truly how social work is, a lot of things have to change. Management by talent contest has routinely pitted employees against each other. Now, rivalry has to be replaced by social capital. For decades, we've tried to motivate people with money, even though we've got a vast amount of research that shows that money erodes social connectedness. Now, we need to let people motivate each other. And for years, we've thought that leaders were heroic soloists who were expected, all by themselves, to solve complex problems. Now, we need to redefine leadership as an activity in which conditions are created in which everyone can do their most courageous thinking together. We know that this works. When the Montreal Protocol called for the phasing out of CFCs, the chlorofluorocarbons implicated in the hole in the ozone layer, the risks were immense. CFCs were everywhere, and nobody knew if a substitute could be found. But one team that rose to the challenge adopted three key principles. The first was the head of engineering, Frank Maslen, said, there will be no stars in this team. We need everybody. Everybody has a valid perspective. Second, we work to one standard only: the best imaginable. And third, he told his boss, Geoff Tudhope, that he had to butt out, because he knew how disruptive power can be. Now, this didn't mean Tudhope did nothing. He gave the team air cover, and he listened to ensure that they honored their principles. And it worked: Ahead of all the other companies tackling this hard problem, this group cracked it first. And to date, the Montreal Protocol is the most successful international environmental agreement ever implemented. There was a lot at stake then, and there's a lot at stake now, and we won't solve our problems if we expect it to be solved by a few supermen or superwomen. Now we need everybody, because it is only when we accept that everybody has value that we will liberate the energy and imagination and momentum we need to create the best beyond measure. Thank you. (Applause)
Este edificio tenía que recibir 2500 caballos pura sangre realmente muy nerviosos que venían de vuelos de larga distancia, con mucho jet lag, y que no estaban en su mejor momento. Los ingenieros enfrentaron este problema: ¿qué cantidad de desechos atender? No enseñan esto en la facultad de ingeniería (Risas) y no es el tipo de cosas en las que uno quisiera equivocarse, podría haber pasado meses hablando con veterinarios, investigando, ajustando la hoja de cálculo. En vez de eso, pidió ayuda y encontró a alguien que había diseñado el Jockey Club de Nueva York. El problema se resolvió en menos de un día. Arup cree que la cultura de la ayuda es central para su éxito. Lo de ayuda suena algo endeble, pero es absolutamente medular para los equipos de éxito, y supera a diario a la inteligencia individual. Ayudar implica que no tengo que saberlo todo, solo tengo que trabajar con personas que saben dar y recibir ayuda. En SAP calculan que pueden responder cualquier pregunta en 17 minutos. Pero no es la única empresa de alta tecnología con la que he trabajado que imagina por un momento que se trata de un problema de tecnología, porque lo que mueve a la ayuda es que la gente se conozca. Suena muy obvio, y pensamos que se dará naturalmente, pero no es así. Cuando gestionaba mi primera empresa de software, me di cuenta de que estábamos estancados. Había mucha fricción, pero no mucho más, y me fui dando cuenta de que las personas brillantes que contraté no se conocían entre ellos. Estaban tan concentrados en su trabajo individual, que ni sabían a quién tenían al lado, y fue entonces que insistí en que dejáramos de trabajar e invirtiéramos tiempo en conocernos unos a otros y que tomaramos impulso de verdad. Eso fue hace 20 años, y ahora visito empresas que han prohibido las tazas de café en los escritorios porque quieren que la gente se reúna en torno a la máquina de café para conversar. Los suecos tienen un término especial para esto. Lo llaman "fika", que significa más que una pausa para el café. Significa "restauración colectiva". En Idexx, una empresa de Maine, han creado huertos en el campus para que las personas de diferentes áreas del negocio puedan trabajar juntos y conocer así todo el negocio. ¿Se han vuelto locos? Todo lo contrario; han advertido que cuando la cosa se complica, y siempre se complicará, si uno hace un trabajo disruptivo que realmente importa, las personas necesitan soporte social, y tienen que saber a quién pedir ayuda. Las empresas no tienen ideas; solo las personas las tienen. Y lo que motiva a las personas son los lazos, la lealtad, y la confianza que desarrollan unos con otros. Importa el mortero, no solo los ladrillos. Cuando juntamos todo esto, tenemos algo llamado capital social. El capital social es la dependencia y la interdependencia que genera confianza. El término viene de los sociólogos que estudiaban las comunidades que eran resistentes en momentos de estrés. El capital social es lo que da impulso a las empresas, el capital social es lo que hace robustas a las empresas. ¿Qué significa esto en la práctica? Significa que el tiempo lo es todo, porque el capital social se compone con el tiempo. A los equipos que trabajan juntos más tiempo, les va mejor porque lleva tiempo desarrollar la confianza necesaria para llegar a la franqueza y la apertura. El tiempo construye valor. Cuando Alex Pentland le sugirió a una empresa que sincronice las pausas para el café para que las personas puedan conversar las ganancias subieron USD 15 millones, y la satisfacción de los empleados subió un 10 %. No es un mal retorno sobre el capital social, y se compone conforme lo gastas. Pero no se trata de camaradería, ni de incentivar vagos, porque las personas que trabajan así suelen ser un poco ásperas, impacientes, absolutamente determinadas a pensar por sí mismas porque esa es su contribución. El conflicto es frecuente porque la franqueza está a salvo. Y así las buenas ideas se vuelven grandes ideas, porque ninguna idea nace ya formada del todo. Emerge un poco como nace un niño, en el caos y la confusión, pero pleno de posibilidades. Y solo gracias a la contribución generosa, la fe y el desafío es que logran su potencial. Eso es lo que apoya el capital social. Pero no solemos hablar de esto, sobre el talento, sobre creatividad, de esta manera. Solemos hablar de estrellas. Por eso empecé a preguntarme: si empezamos a trabajar así, ¿implica el fin de las estrellas? Y fui a las audiciones en la Real Academia de Arte Dramático de Londres. Y allí vi algo que me sorprendió, porque los profesores no buscaban pirotecnia individual. Buscaban lo que ocurría entre los estudiantes, porque en eso yace el drama. Y hablando con productores de álbumes exitosos, me dijeron: "Claro, tenemos muchas superestrellas de la música. pero no perduran demasiado. Solo los colaboradores destacados disfrutan de largas carreras, porque sacando lo mejor de los otros es como encuentran lo mejor en ellos". Y cuando fui a visitar empresas célebres por su ingenio y creatividad, no encontré superestrellas, porque todos allí importaban. Y al reflexionar sobre mi propia carrera, y las personas extraordinarias con las que tuve el privilegio de trabajar, me di cuenta de cuánto más podríamos darnos mutuamente si dejáramos de tratar de ser supergallinas. (Risas) (Aplausos) Una vez que uno aprecia de verdad cómo es el trabajo social, muchas cosas tienen que cambiar. La gestión por concurso de talentos ha enfrentado de manera rutinaria a los empleados unos contra otros. La rivalidad tiene que ser reemplazada por el capital social. Durante décadas, hemos intentado motivar a las personas con dinero, a pesar de contar con gran cantidad de investigación que muestra que el dinero erosiona la conexión social. Ahora, tenemos que dejar que las personas motiven a los demás. Durante años, pensamos que los líderes eran héroes solitarios y se esperaba que por sí mismos, resolvieran problemas complejos. Tenemos que redefinir el liderazgo como una actividad en la que se crean las condiciones para que cada uno pueda brindar el pensamiento más valiente, juntos. Sabemos que eso funciona. Cuando el Protocolo de Montreal llamó a la eliminación gradual de los CFC, los clorofluorocarbonos implicados en el agujero en la capa de ozono, los riesgos eran inmensos. Los CFC estaban por doquier, y nadie sabía si se podía encontrar un sustituto. Pero un equipo que aceptó el reto adoptó 3 principios clave. El primero fue el jefe de ingeniería, Frank Maslen, que dijo: no habrá estrellas en este equipo. Necesitamos a todos. Todo el mundo tiene una perspectiva válida. Segundo, trabajamos con una norma única: lo mejor imaginable. Y tercero, le dijo a su jefe, Geoff Tudhope, que tenía que alejarse, porque sabía lo perjudicial que puede ser el poder. Esto no significó que Tudhope no hiciera nada. Le dio cobertura al equipo, y escuchaba para garantizar que honraban sus principios. Funcionó: Por delante de otras empresas que abordaron este difícil problema, este grupo lo hizo primero. Hasta la fecha, el Protocolo de Montreal es el acuerdo ambiental de mayor éxito internacional implementado en la historia. Había mucho en juego entonces, y hay mucho en juego ahora, y no resolveremos nuestros problemas si esperamos que sea resuelto por unos pocos superhombres o supermujeres. Necesitamos a todos, porque solo cuando aceptemos que todos tenemos un valor será cuando liberaremos la energía, la imaginación y el impulso necesarios para crear lo mejor inconmensurable. Gracias. (Aplausos)